Now let's talk a little about middle activities or medium activities which are basically teaching a concept.
They're a little bit more than ice breaking activities, although a lot of them could be ice breaking activities, and they're not really so much testing activities.
The first one I want to talk about it called Pass the Face.
You have everybody sit in a circle, they're all sitting down and one person is going to make a face.
Like a happy face or a sad face or an angry face and then everybody in the circle repeats that face.
So I make a sad face, the sad face goes all the way around the room.
Then the person next to me might make a funny face and it goes all around the circle and then the next person might make an angry face, all the way around the circle everybody repeats the angry face.
So we go all around the circle with everyone getting to make a face, we pass all the faces so everybody gets to do the faces and then we can talk about emotions.
What face did you make?
Well, I made a happy face.
Why?
Cause I'm really happy today.
Well I made an angry face because I'm really mad that I missed the bus this morning or whatever it is.
So this is a wonderful way to teach emotions by letting the kids experience and show the emotions that they're feeling or the emotions that they wanted to express in that moment.